<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Courses | Xuerui Wang</title>
    <link>/course/</link>
      <atom:link href="/course/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Courses</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Courses</title>
      <link>/course/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>AE3200 Design Synthesis (DSE)</title>
      <link>/course/dse/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/course/dse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the BSc graduation project of TU Delft. To finalise their bachelor programme third-year bachelor’s students at the Faculty of Aerospace Engineering are required to collaborate in groups of ten students in a period of ten weeks to make a design in the field of aviation, space, earth observation or related field. During the project, students go through the complete design process, from drawing up a program of demands, concept analysis and design, concept selection to the presentation of the final design. I acted as the principal instructor for Group 26, a ten-student project entitled &amp;ldquo;Air-Guard, A bio-inspired counter-drone morphing UAV&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AERO0003 Flight Dynamics and Control</title>
      <link>/course/belgium/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/course/belgium/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a MSc profile course at the University of Liège, Belgium. This course focuces on the flight dynamics and control of fixed-wing aircaft and helicopter. I was invited by 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=i7puvt4AAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;oi=sra&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Grigorios Dimitriadis&lt;/a&gt; and 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://scholar.google.com/citations?user=hWAm2FEAAAAJ&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;oi=ao&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Prof. Christophe Collette&lt;/a&gt; to give three four-hour lectures physically at the University of Liège. My lectures cover the control design as well as stability and robustness analysis of fixed-wing and helicopter aircraft flight control.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WM0324LR Ethics and Engineering for Aerospace</title>
      <link>/course/ethics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/course/ethics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an MSc profile course. This course describes and analyses the responsibility of engineers in the light of philosophical, historical and juridical backgrounds. Topics covered include 1) Description and analysis of the problems encountered by engineers who want to act responsibly; 2) Codes of ethics for engineers. 3) Argumentation and reasoning. 4) Uncertainty, ignorance, risks, and their implications for responsible behaviour. 5) (Philosophical) ethics, the foundation of (criteria) for good and bad, right and wrong, responsible and irresponsible behaviour; 6) Responsibility within and of organizations; 7) the role of law. Since 2021, I act as a tutor and essay supervisor for the course in every Q3.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AE4311 Non-linear and Adaptive Flight Control</title>
      <link>/course/ae4311/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/course/ae4311/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is an MSc elective course. It introduces nonlinear and adaptive control techniques to enhance the reconfigurability of aircraft flight control systems. Advanced nonlinear and adaptive control techniques such as Adaptive Nonlinear Dynamic Inversion (ANDI), Incremental Nonlinear Dynamic Inversion (INDI), Adaptive Backstepping (ABS) and Incremental Backstepping are described together with applications to fault-tolerant and reconfigurable aircraft flight control system designs. I am a guest lecturer for the INDI control theory part in every Q4 since 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AE4ASM522 Applied Aircraft Aeroelasticity</title>
      <link>/course/ae4asm522/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/course/ae4asm522/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This course is an MSc elective as a follow-up of AE4ASM506 Fundamentals of Aeroelasticity. This course presents three more advanced topics in aeroelasticity. 1) nonlinear aeroelasticity; 2) flexible aircraft flight dynamics; 3) panel methods. Understanding the contents of this course will prepare the student for the design of future aircraft configurations. Since 2020, I am in charge of the design, teaching, and assessment of the flexible aircraft flight dynamics and a part of nonlinear aeroelasticity in every Q4.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AE2235-II Signal Analysis and Telecommunication Principles</title>
      <link>/course/ae2235signal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/course/ae2235signal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a BSc course that focuses on signal acquisition, processing and filtering. By learning this course, students will be able to apply frequency domain techniques to signal conditioning and processing, know building blocks and electronic components, apply signal modulation, produce a signal link budget, evaluate stability properties of closed and open-loop systems, and tune control systems with classical tuning methods. It also contains an experimental classroom, in which real-world derives including Light Sensor under a Rotating Disc, Accelerometer on a Cantilever Beam, Rate Gyro on a Pendulum, Pressure Sensor behind a Propeller that help students to understand Fourier transforms, aliasing, leakage, etc. Since 2017, I act an experimental classroom tutor in every Q4.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
